Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
Sorry we couldn't give you
more notice of the move. lads.
but that's what you
get for being category a.
You'll like it down south. though.
I mean. they'll kick
the livin' shit out of you.
But there's less rain.
You probably think it's a city.
Liverpool.
But it's not.
It's a village.
So when they need
people like you in liver pool.
they have to take them
from the same place as us.
the same streets.
So don't you worry
about the move. mate.
We had plenty of notice.
- You shake my shoulders
- nobody fucking move!
You shake the earth you shake my life
for all it's worth
go! Go! Go. go. go! Go. go!
Go! Come on!
Come on. let's go! Fucking go!
Come on! Go! Go. now! Come on. now!
Irresistible force brings me back to you.
Maybe it's my fault.
Maybe I should've taken the time
during your training to explain that.
it would be very much appreciated
if. while you're performing your duties.
you do your level best not
to burn down any houses.
It's fine.
It's a lot of things. son.
but it is not fucking fine.
We signed Shaun off sick.
and got him and his family
a long way from Manchester.
And I placed a story through a Manchester
press agency calling it a house fire.
You think you got away with it? Let
me tell you somethin' about this game.
You never get away with anythin'.
All you can do is wait and
see how much it's cost you.
Whatever they did. it's worked.
The Turks say they're gonna send
a load to felixstowe. a proper load.
Doesn't matter what the Turks say.
Until that load's on that boat. it's not real.
so get it on the bloody boat.
And we need to firm
up the evidence now.
You've got a lot on Carter's
team but not a lot on Carter.
and now you need to
find a new way of getting it.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Well. if you're not. you need to tell
me. 'cause it's only gonna get worse.
I said I'm all right. didn't I?
Right.
How did they do that. then?
A bent screw tipped 'em
off about their transfer.
Got themselves sprung from the Van.
Didn't think they had
the minerals for that.
- They'll come for us.
- For me?
They're not that fuckin' stupid.
They'll be halfway to
Spain in the boot of a car.
But we don't risk it.
We're done with this place. for a start.
Get everythin' out of here. then torch it.
Find some safe houses for the gear.
- Where?
- From our loyal customers.
Doubt they'll drive a hard bargain.
what with them being smack heads.
That's all the gear we've got
till the Turks come through.
Look after it.
Car keys. company paperwork.
and the mail you wanted.
Thanks.
Listen. what happened to
Shaun's on the both of us.
We need to incriminate Carter.
We can't get back into his gang.
We haven't got an informer.
so we need to go directly to him
and try and find a way to
incriminate him before it's too late.
One of the best things we could do
for Shaun right now is to calm down.
- And...
- he tried to kill a kid. Bailey.
When Carter found out about Shaun.
he tried to kill Shaun and his
wife and his kid because of us.
- Carter didn't kill anyone because of us.
- He didn't blink before givin' that order.
So now I'm goin' back
in with him on my own.
protected by a few bits of
paper. and I will fuckin' do it. too.
Because he tried to kill a kid.
Okay.
So what's your plan?
He wants to get into a
world that won't 'ave him.
I know a bit about that.
So I'm gonna make myself a
representation of that world.
I'm gonna try and find a weakness.
And I'm gonna try not to fall
over in these bloody shoes.
Good luck. mate.
Thanks.
Hello.
It's the switchboard. We've
got someone on the line
wanting to speak to whoever
was working with Shaun?
Put them through.
Hello?
16 Walker road on the boot estate.
There's two kilos of smack
under the kitchen floorboards.
Two kilos of heroin
under the floorboards.
- So what are you waiting for?
- It could be a trap.
Of course it could be a
trap. What couldn't be a trap?
- So how do I do it?
- Very carefully.
Which means don't
call anyone in liver pool.
I'll get you a police
contact in Manchester.
And remember. if you're watching them.
that probably means
they're watching you.
…main story today.
The prime minister has denied
that splits are forming in her cabinet
as her economic policies
continue to prove unpopular.
Go and find the others.
See if they need some
help movin' the stuff.
- Floor?
- Five.
- Come on!
- Fuck off. you bizzie wankers!
- Get off!
- Get off him. you fuckin' prick!
- Hands behind your back.
- What? It's not mine!
- Stop resisting.
- You're 'urtin' me!
Get up. you... yeah. that's right. fuck off!
- Well?
- It was legit.
Good.
Now what do you do?
Get to whoever told me about
it. see what else they'll tell me.
Correct.
It's a delicate dance. that one. son.
And… I'm glad it's you doin' it.
Thanks.
Good luck.
What's goin' on?
You have never asked
me why I was in prison.
It is a long story.
Yeah. some bloke asked for
protection money. so you shot him.
That is the short story.
When's the load gettin' shipped?
No. you will not ask that.
You know. maybe… you are tired.
Maybe you want this to end. to go home.
But the man you pretend to
be. the man they think you are.
he would know that
these things take time.
Why is nothin' happenin'?
He would not ask that either.
He would know that. in this world.
something is always happening.
And if you don't know what is happening.
then it is probably happening to you.
Guy. the English. he's gone.
We need him.
For now.
Then we learn what he does.
then he's gone.
- And we do what he does.
- Who?
Who will do what he does?
Zeki.
Baba. this is learning the systems.
setting up companies.
dealing with customs.
Zeki is a hooligan.
What is this? Hooligan?
You are too English.
You read their newspapers.
You think like them.
Do you know what we call a
hooligan. where we are from?
We call him a delikanlı.
A man.
The longer you live here.
the more Turkish you get.
Do you even remember
where you're from?
I remember being poor. baba.
I remember being hungry.
England has given us what we have.
And now it can give us even
more. if we work together.
I have given us what we have.
We work with Turks.
If we work with English. it is
only to learn what they know.
Then they're gone.
You think too little of the English.
And too much of the Turks.
- Why?
- Because hakan is old.
And Aziz is weak.
It is time for a change. and
Aziz cannot be the change.
We have known hakan for a long time.
Then you know his limits.
Hakan has come a long
way from where he started.
but he is an old man in a new world.
In what we do. there is more
money to be made than ever before.
Hakan and Aziz want to share
that money with the English.
I want to share it with you.
There is nothing more dangerous in
this world than a kurd with a grudge.
If hakan knew that we talked like this.
he would kill us all.
Hakan will never know.
He will not be around to find out.
Neither will Aziz.
Neither will anyone who does
not agree that this is the solution.
You can do that?
I can do it.
I just need to know
that when I have done it.
then we will work together.
Then let us know when it's done.
Thanks for joining me. sir.
You're the organizer of Saturday's
anti-drugs march in liver pool?
Yeah. absolutely. Wayne
Duffy. community organizer.
Well. it looks like it's going
to be the largest protest yet.
What do you hope to achieve?
We wanna send a
message to the drug dealers
that the people of liver pool
don't want them on their estates.
- That we're fightin' back.
- Right!
The police won't do their job. so
we will. We're the ones that live here.
We know who's to blame for
this. We know what to do about it.
We'll get smack off our
streets and protect our kids.
and if the dealers think we're joking.
they'll soon find out how serious we are.
- That's right. Wayne.
- Yes. Wayne!
Got your post.
Sorry.
- You're new.
- Yeah.
- You're not from liver pool?
- No. I'm here with work.
What's that?
Property development.
What kind of property?
Regeneration projects.
We look for post-industrial spaces
we can rezone for residential.
Well. you're in the right city for that.
- Where does the money come from?
- Private investors.
I do some investment meself.
We're not looking for
additional funding right now.
- No?
- No.
I wouldn't just be… any kind of investor.
See. I know liver pool. I know
where the opportunities are.
I know more about this city
than you could ever know.
No matter how long you spend
here. no matter how hard you look.
So you're local. then?
Not to round 'ere. no.
No. I'm from real liver pool.
All the places you'll be
buyin' up and knockin' down.
So why are you here and not there?
'Cause I used to tell my mum that
I'd buy her somewhere round 'ere.
Used to tell her that.
She never believed me.
Well. she must be
very proud of you now.
She's dead. They were all posted
on the same day.
Sorry?
Your letters. they were all postmarked
on the same day. through
the same sortin' office.
That's a bit…
Unusual. isn't it?
I've no idea.
Thank you for bringing
them over. though.
Just…
Hello?
The o'connells aren't in
Spain. and they are taking us on.
Who?
Jed.
There's a couple of lads missing
too. but they wanted us to see jed.
We need to meet.
I'm on my way.
Sorry. I've gotta… gotta go.
I'll see you around.
Yeah.
Yeah. you will.
We need to find the
o'connells before they find us.
We'll find 'em.
What happened to
the Walker road stash?
It's like you said. Carter.
They're smack heads.
The bizzies probably slipped
them a tenner more than we did.
- Gonna keep my head down for a few days.
- Good idea.
You're coming with me.
- That a problem?
- No.
Good.
Thank you for coming.
We have good news.
- It's on its way?
- Soon. but first. zeki has a plan.
Great.
I have a guard at
felixstowe docks. A turk.
He will help us. There'll be no
more problems. Not like last time.
Last time was fine.
The lesson of last time is
that I deal with importations.
I don't need your help. and I don't
need some bent guard gettin' in the way.
Why would you not want our
help? You do not trust a turk?
I have a system. This is not the system.
Maybe you worry he will tell us that
you do not know what you say you know.
- This is a bad idea.
- Let's meet the guard.
Then we can decide what is a bad idea.
I will arrange it. hakan.
I need you to run through every
employee at felixstowe customs
and find any with a Turkish surname.
- Where do we draw the line?
- Sorry?
I'll need to set parameters.
Jesus Christ. it's very bloody simple.
Do any Turks work at felixstowe docks?
No. it's not simple.
Turkish surnames spread far
beyond the country's borders.
so if I went by nationality.
I'd risk missing someone.
which could lead to you being put in
mortal danger. which would be my fault.
So. seeing as you're investigating kurds.
I suggest you'd include
Iraq. Syria. and Iran.
and seeing as you don't
have a clue about any of this.
I'd suggest you don't tell me
that my job is bloody simple.
You're doing a good job.
Someone should tell you that.
Do you need me to tell
you you're doing a good job?
No.
So why would I?
Yeah.
Think I'll go back to green lanes.
Safer than 'ere.
- How long for?
- Just a couple of nights.
We've taken over the doors
of a few clubs down there.
- You're gonna miss it.
- Miss what?
The march.
You've gotta be there. Eddie. We owe
it to Tommy to stand up for kids like him.
And tell those scumbag
dealers their time's up.
It's just a couple of nights. all right?
Hello?
27 wood street in huyton.
There's ten kilos in the shed.
No.
You what?
We can find our own busts.
Bollocks you can.
Look. I want Carter.
and I think you do too.
And I need more than this to get him.
- Why are you doing this?
- Because of what he's done to this city.
To the families.
- Let's meet. We can sort somethin' out.
- Ten kilos in the shed.
Yes?
I need all heroin deaths
in liver pool in the last year.
Names. addresses. next of kin.
Families.
Good evening. sir.
Look at this. mate.
Then think about us. workin' the doors.
Monday nights. two in the mornin'.
Freezin' our tits off for 20 quid
and the chance of getting
knifed up by some pissed-off kid.
And I told you there
was more to life than that.
Now here we are.
In a suite at the adelphi.
We're at the adelphi 'cause there
are bullets out there with our names on.
That's good. It's only when people come
for you. you get to show your strength.
This is an opportunity.
To send a message.
To remind people how far we've come.
Didn't have to come
this far. though. did we?
We could've stopped
after taking over the doors.
We could've stopped with the weed.
You couldn't stop. though.
could you? Now 'ere we are.
You're on the couch.
Sleep facin' the door.
How is she?
- Fine.
- Fine?
- No.
- What do you mean. no?
I mean that I don't want
you distracted. not by us.
So she's fine. and she'll
always be fine until you're back.
Come on. tell me what it is.
or I'll think it's somethin' worse.
She's just nervous. you
know. about the recital.
That today?
Yeah.
She don't get nervous.
"She don't get nervous."
She doesn't.
Mum! We're gonna be late!
Well. now she does. but that's for me
to deal with. and I've gotta go. Love you.
Love you.
I want the o'connells
taken care of by tonight.
I've got half of liver pool looking for them.
It'll end today.
One way or the other.
- Hi.
- No Turks at felixstowe customs.
Right.
- Is that bad?
- Well. it ain't good.
Right… is there anything
else I can help with?
I've gotta go.
Hello?
It's bar an. May peace be upon you.
And peace upon you. bar an.
It has happened. hakan. just
like you always said it would.
Who?
They're comin'.
Okay. let's go.
Let them go.
You were right. English.
He gets in the way.
Do you know what. mate?
Lot of places I could be right now.
A lot of places I should be.
The back of a dry cleaner's
in green lanes ain't one of 'em.
I'm 'ere to do business.
and he ain't my problem.
Do what you want with him.
and let me know when
you're ready to start work.
Who else was involved?
Istanbul.
Good. You did not lie.
Please. hakan.
I wanted you to take me seriously. to
see I can do more than you let me do.
That is all.
It was a mistake.
And I am a kurd. hakan.
Those other two were
not. but I. I am a kurd.
We are united by blood.
Don't worry. zeki.
I never killed a kurd. and
I'm too old to start now.
Thank you. hakan.
Okay.
You are entrusted to god.
Well. the short answer
is we're close. Very close.
Seeing as I've been
summoned to the home secretary.
I think I might trouble
you for the long answer.
Well. the load's coming soon.
and we're working hard to make
sure the evidence arrives first.
But I think we've reached the
stage. sir. where I need to protect you.
What does that mean?
It means I can give you more.
or you can look him in the eye
when you tell him you
don't have more to give him.
We're in a race. Don.
between us succeeding and our political
and financial support running out.
and I don't think we're winning.
With what our lot are out there
doing. with what they're becoming.
I think we'll get there.
We just need to hold our nerve.
And how's that going?
- How… how are they holding up. mentally?
- Fine.
- And they're not in too deep?
- No.
- You know why I'm asking.
- They're doing fine.
And you know why I'm asking you.
It's because of what happened to me
that I know it hasn't happened to them.
Not yet. anyway.
Made it. then.
- Hello. mate. How are you?
- Hi.
She's all right. Just a little nervous.
Thanks for coming.
No. you don't thank me for that. This is…
This is my job.
There you are. Lily. Come along now.
Take it easy. mate.
She's just saying hello.
You can speak to your
children after the recital.
It's all right. She'll be all right.
Well. that was quite the
range of performance.
I'll just take a moment to gather my
thoughts ahead of the presentation.
Please help yourself to
tea and coffee at the back.
- I've been working away.
- Sorry?
Which is hard for a kid.
Hard for a wife too. It affects 'em.
More than I'd like to
think. more than they let on.
There is something you'd like to discuss?
- This is hardly the setting...
- but I have to ignore all that.
I have to shut that out.
which isn't easy. but I need to
do it. or the whole thing falls apart.
You see. I can't have guilt.
I can't have that goin' on
while everythin' else is goin' on.
It would be dangerous
for me to have guilt.
which means it would be dangerous
for anyone who puts that guilt inside me.
Are you… are you threatening me?
Course not.
I'm just sayin' that life ain't easy
right now for that girl out there.
And you could make it a little easier.
And I would very
much like you to do that.
Now wash your hands.
- Yeah?
- We have a meeting.
Meetin' with who?
It is dangerous for both of us.
but it had to happen one day.
and it will happen today.
Guy?
Go on. then. What's the address?
- What's this?
- The march.
Fuckin' idiots.
And with Wayne Duffy
as their glorious leader.
I remember Duffy.
Community organizer?
He's a piss head from croxteth.
Carryin' on like he's Robin hood.
Turn round.
It's always the dealers gettin' it in the
neck. isn't it? What about the parents?
It's not our fault they can't
keep their kids off fuckin' smack.
We need to get out of 'ere.
It's them.
Shit.
Watch my fuckin' washin'!
Dealers out! Save our streets!
Save our streets!
Split up! If you get a chance. do 'em!
I'm not tooled! It's in
the car. so fucking run!
Save our streets! Dealers out!
Easy.
Okay?
Put those away. There's kids about.
Shoulda come with us. Eddie.
You should be a long way from liver pool.
Once we've dealt with Carter. we'll
be on our toes. and you should too.
They were gonna kill us inside. Eddie.
Dealers are the lowest of the
low in there since that kid died.
It's the way this game's goin'.
Leverage.
That's what you two have got.
Doing Carter and going back
inside for life is not a good use of it.
Listen to me.
There are things happenin' that
don't need messed up by you two.
And being on your toes is
expensive. so there's a deal to be done.
And you need to go to Carter
with it. but not through me.
All right. good win?
Let's go.
- What?
- We need to meet.
It's important.
Fine. Usual place. I'm comin' now.
The o'connells want 200 grand
and a pair of knocked-off passports.
I can get 'em the passports.
You can get 'em the money.
- Why didn't you Nick them?
- 'Cause they knew to come to me.
Which makes me wonder
what else they know.
And it's confusing. 'cause
no one knows about me.
No one's met me apart from you.
- So who sent them to me?
- I don't know.
I do know I pay you to
get rid of problems like this.
I'm tellin' you how to get rid of it.
200 grand to get shot of those
two is a bargain. and you know it.
- You're in enough trouble as it is.
- Yeah?
Look around ya. This
city is turnin' on you lot.
You think some poxy march led by
that prick Duffy's gonna take me down?
People are listenin' to Duffy. Your people.
And if they turn on you.
they start pickin' up the phone to us.
and it might not be me who answers.
I control this city. I think
that's been forgotten.
By you.
by the o'connells.
by Duffy.
Maybe you all need help to remember it.
If you do have control. that
would be the quickest way to lose it.
Do the deal. son.
Silver Ford granada.
registration starting a69.
- That's it.
- But that's only three characters.
I was lucky to get that.
Look for liver pool addresses
and criminal records.
- Okay. - Thanks.
We are closing in on a
large heroin importation.
and the subsequent arrests and dismantling
of two highly significant drugs networks.
- How much of that can be said publicly?
- Nothing.
Let me try again. How much of that
can be said publicly by the prime minister?
Nothing.
Our party conference
begins this evening.
and the prime minister has
never faced a more important one.
The cabinet is split. The gray
men are plotting against her.
They think she is weak. replaceable.
She will show them that she is not.
She understands the British
people better than any of us.
She knows they need something to fear
in order to see her as their protector.
She's planning a show of strength.
A little red meat for the masses.
She will make the war on drugs
the centerpiece of her speech.
With all due respect. home secretary.
that timing is potentially unhelpful.
If the… if the criminal networks think
security is to be temporarily
heightened at the borders.
then they may delay or even abort...
this is not about your operation. Blake.
This is about a prime
minister fighting for her life.
Watch her speech this evening.
Watch the faces of the
plotters. of the gray men.
and you will understand that
you are now a cog in the machine.
Of course. such a
speech demands results.
We have three months left of
our agreed operational timescale.
This is politics. Things
change. You have three weeks.
At which point. the prime
minister can announce your results.
or she can announce the merging
of customs anti-drug operations
with the metropolitan police.
My team are not cogs. home secretary.
They're men and women.
and they're out there in the field.
And this is not about votes.
and it's not about… gray men.
It's about the safety of my team.
Your comments are noted.
And you never know. Blake.
she might decide to give
kinnock another kicking instead.
But if she goes with the war on
drugs. then you have three weeks.
Do it.
Do what?
Pay 'em off.
- Never thought I'd see you scared.
- Don't be soft. lad.
We don't show weakness.
We pay them off. that's
the beginning of the end.
We need them out the way to
do what we need with the Turks.
What if I tell you to
get them out the way?
I'd say that's not the way to go.
And you think that'll be
me snookered. do you?
Think I can't get me hands dirty?
I'm saying there's a time to get
your hands dirty. and this isn't it.
What the Turks are offering is big
enough to get us out this game forever.
- Is that right? You want out now. do ya?
- Yeah! I do!
And don't be telling me you don't.
You've got plans. Carter. You've got
a life that you want. and this isn't it.
The money from the
Turks can give you that.
You used to tell me you was gonna
own half of liver pool. How's that goin'?
You're right.
This is a step to somethin' else.
and it is gonna end sometime.
but it's gonna end on my terms.
and I will not be threatened by
anyone. Eddie. and that includes you.
Hey. I'm tryin' to help you.
Protect you. just like I always have.
The bizzies have hit
the stash in wood street.
That's ten kilos.
Fuck is goin' on?
I'll handle that.
You do the deal.
Twenty-three Ford granada owners in
the liver pool area with that registration.
Law-abiding. taxpaying
citizens. half of them women.
and a surprising number of doctors.
If they're crooks. they're hiding it well.
- And that's the lot? - Yeah.
Apart from public
authority vehicles. Sorry.
It's not your fault.
mate. Thanks for trying.
- I've blown it.
- No. you haven't.
That was Carter's connection. and
I couldn't even get a full reg plate.
- What?
- Look at this.
- Fuckin' hell.
- Yeah.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna go try and
turn that into something.
Shouldn't we tell
someone or get support?
No. This is what I'm here to do.
And I'm gonna do it.
Keys.
Yep.
You're handsome. He did not
say that you were handsome.
It is too late.
The cinnamon must go in with the meat.
If not. you do not get the flavor.
It is too late.
- Cinnamon for my Princess.
- It is too late.
It is never too late.
You leave me alone with
such a handsome man?
I was keeping him safe.
You think he's safe with me?
How are you. my friend?
Welcome to my home.
Well. tonight…
You have a treat.
Tonight. we eat Afghan food.
Made the old way. with
the cinnamon added late.
Is that right?
Yamas.
Here. another.
Yes?
It's a funny thing. innit.
blokes and control?
They all want more than they have.
and they've all got less than they think.
- Right…
- But then there's Carter.
He thinks he's in control of a whole city.
And the difference with him
is… I reckon he might be right.
He's been a step ahead
of us the whole time.
He has.
Which means he's had information.
Did you have a question?
- Public authority vehicles.
- Yes.
Does that include police?
It does. Why?
He's got a cop.
Mr. President. there are
always new dangers to be faced.
new battles to be fought.
We're at war against drugs.
against those who produce drugs.
against those who peddle drugs.
against those who launder
the profits of the drug trade.
Drugs stunt young lives.
They break up families.
They injure babies
before they're even born.
There are those in britain who
say we should legalize certain drugs.
as though burglary could be
defeated by legalizing theft.
I never thought I'd agree
with bloody Thatcher.
How typical of the muddled
thinking of the so-called progressives.
In fact. such action would expose
many more of our young people
to the danger of drugs.
We must…
Eddie.
Will it just be you?
Yeah.
I'll be in touch.
I will let you two gentlemen talk.
Thank you. koukla mou.
That was lovely. Thanks.
- You liked the food. then?
- No. Why am I here?
You are here so you are not out there.
What's happenin' out there?
Some of it is happening.
Some of it… has already happened.
None of it can be stopped.
What have you done?
What have we done?
You know… my friend.
there is no greater risk in this world
than thinking you have
power that you do not have.
Because that creates confusion.
and there must be no confusion.
It must be clear who has the power.
And then.
the only decision left
is how to use it.
No!
Zeki…
About fucking time.
Hello. boys.
This is from Carter.
I don't have to sell my soul
there were thousands of them.
It was like bloody zulu. They
just kept comin' over the hill.
I tell ya. people will remember this day.
They'll remember it. This was
the day that liver pool changed.
Wayne.
I wanna be adored
fuck. Lad. lad. lad. Lad!
Fuck!
Lad!
Adored.
I wanna be adored you adore me
you adore me
you adore me. I wanna I
wanna. I wanna be adored
I wanna. I wanna I wanna
be adored I wanna. I wanna
I wanna be adored I wanna.
I wanna I gotta be adored.
I wanna be. I wanna be. I wanna be.
I wanna be adored
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today